<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>projects on Yash Raj Singh</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/categories/projects/</link><description>Recent content in projects on Yash Raj Singh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Yash Raj Singh</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yashrajsingh.net/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UK Weather Analyzer</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/2016/08/uk-weather-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrajsingh.net/2016/08/uk-weather-analyzer/</guid><description>10K UK Weather Analyzer and Visualization In October 2016, I participated &amp;amp; won ‘Best Technical Award’ in the prestigious 10K Apart Challenge of 2016.
10K Apart International Challenge by Microsoft &amp;amp; An Event Apart is about building a compelling web experience that can be delivered in 10kB and works without JavaScript.
About 380 entries took part from around the globe, judged by some of the best developers, designers of the industry.</description></item><item><title>TellMeWeatherNow!</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/2015/09/tellmeweathernow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrajsingh.net/2015/09/tellmeweathernow/</guid><description>TellMeWeatherNow! TellMeWeatherNow!
In September, 2014 I solved a challenge for selection of GopherConIndia 2015 scholars, I had to create a web based application for showing Weather updates for 5 cities concurrently, in Golang using Go Routines for concurrency.
I did got selected as a Student Scholar. You can view the code on GitHub.
Google App Engine with Go I used an online weather API available freely for use, for fetching the data.</description></item><item><title>ideaPad</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/2014/08/ideapad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrajsingh.net/2014/08/ideapad/</guid><description>ideaPad ideaPad for Android
ideaPad is an easy-to-use, app that helps you remember your greatest ideas. Quickly save your ideas or to-do&amp;rsquo;s, Answer sample questions, draw sketches - that&amp;rsquo;s the magic. It helps you gain momentum on your life goals and ideas. I build the app in August 2014, because i needed a place where i could store my ideas.
Hopefully so they won&amp;rsquo;t get lost in time and i would work on them.</description></item><item><title>Equilibrium</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/2014/05/equilibrium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrajsingh.net/2014/05/equilibrium/</guid><description>Equilibrium Equilibrium - gcdc2013
In 2013, I participated in Google Cloud Developers Challenge 2013 and was selected as the internation finalist in the competition.
I build an application for managing projects deadlines within a company. I called it Equilibrium. I won 1000$, Nexus Tablet and other goodies from Google(Yay! Score).
Google App Engine with Python Equilibrium is build on Google App engine with Python, also utilizing (Google+, Wikipedia, Google Custom Search, Google Maps) API&amp;rsquo;s for various functions.</description></item><item><title>Project Yello</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/2013/06/project-yello/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrajsingh.net/2013/06/project-yello/</guid><description>Project Yello Project Yello
In June 2014, I started working on Project Yello, The idea was simple. While my time in college, i realized that there is a huge gap between &amp;lsquo;what student learned&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;what student is taught&amp;rsquo;.
The things we were taught in college, were of no use most of the times, because students didn&amp;rsquo;t worked on projects i.e. to apply that knowledge they learned atleast once, so they would get a better prespective of how, why, when, what of that knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Host your Resume on Google App Engine</title><link>https://yashrajsingh.net/2016/07/host-your-resume-on-google-app-engine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrajsingh.net/2016/07/host-your-resume-on-google-app-engine/</guid><description>I made a little boilerplate over the weekend, for people who are searching for jobs and want to build a customized resume for a specific company.
The idea is very simple, since to stand out amoung the applicants you need to be visible and you can be visible by making a specific web page (since its responsive and available through the internet) describing about yourself and how you stand out from others, plus how the company can benefit from your skills and services.</description></item></channel></rss>