<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>challenge on Yash</title><link>https://yashrs.com/tags/challenge/</link><description>Recent content in challenge on Yash</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Yash Raj Singh</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yashrs.com/tags/challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UK Weather Analyzer</title><link>https://yashrs.com/2016/08/uk-weather-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrs.com/2016/08/uk-weather-analyzer/</guid><description>10K UK Weather Analyzer and Visualization In October 2016, I participated &amp;amp; won ‘Best Technical Award’ in the prestigious 10K Apart Challenge of 2016.
10K Apart International Challenge by Microsoft &amp;amp; An Event Apart is about building a compelling web experience that can be delivered in 10kB and works without JavaScript.
About 380 entries took part from around the globe, judged by some of the best developers, designers of the industry.</description></item><item><title>TellMeWeatherNow!</title><link>https://yashrs.com/2015/09/tellmeweathernow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrs.com/2015/09/tellmeweathernow/</guid><description>TellMeWeatherNow! TellMeWeatherNow!
In September, 2014 I solved a challenge for selection of GopherConIndia 2015 scholars, I had to create a web based application for showing Weather updates for 5 cities concurrently, in Golang using Go Routines for concurrency.
I did got selected as a Student Scholar. You can view the code on GitHub.
Google App Engine with Go I used an online weather API available freely for use, for fetching the data.</description></item><item><title>Equilibrium</title><link>https://yashrs.com/2014/05/equilibrium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashrs.com/2014/05/equilibrium/</guid><description>Equilibrium Equilibrium - gcdc2013
In 2013, I participated in Google Cloud Developers Challenge 2013 and was selected as the internation finalist in the competition.
I build an application for managing projects deadlines within a company. I called it Equilibrium. I won 1000$, Nexus Tablet and other goodies from Google(Yay! Score).
Google App Engine with Python Equilibrium is build on Google App engine with Python, also utilizing (Google+, Wikipedia, Google Custom Search, Google Maps) API&amp;rsquo;s for various functions.</description></item></channel></rss>